[Music]
if you intentionally expose people to
Mercury by feeding them fish like tuna
for 14 weeks and then stop this is what
happens to the level of mercury in their
bloodstream it goes up up up and then as
soon as you stop the fish it drops back
down such that you can detox down half
in about 100 days so the half life of
total mercury in your blood it's
approximately 100 days so even if you
eat a lot of fish within a few months of
stopping you can clear much of it out of
your blood but what about out of your
brain modeling studies are all over the
place suggesting half- lives similar to
blood at 69 days all the way up to 22
years but when you put it to the test
autopsy studies suggest it may even be
longer still once Mercury gets into your
brain it can be decades before your body
can get rid of even half of it so better
than detoxing is to not tox in the first
place that's the problem with these fish
advisories where they tell pregnant
women to cut down on fish for pollutants
with long half lives like pcbs and
dioxins temporary decreases in fish
consumption daily contaminate intake
will not necessarily translate to
appreciable decreases in maternal
persistent organic plant body burden
which is what helps determine the dose
that the baby gets for example here's
how much exposure an infant gets to a
tumor promoting pollutant called PCB 153
if their mom ate fish but if for one
year mom ate only half the fish or no
fish at all it wouldn't budge levels
much only if Mom cut out all fish for
five years before do you see a really
substantial drop in infant levels so
that's the fish consumption caveat
the only scenarios that produced a
significant impact on children's
exposures required mothers to eliminate
fish from their diets completely for 5
years before their children were
conceived substituting plant Foods
instead of fish would reduce prenatal
and and breastfeeding exposures by 37%
each and subsequent childhood exposures
by 23% so a complete ban on fish
consumption maybe preferable to targeted
life stage-based fish consump
advisories but if you are going to eat
fish Which is less polluted wildau or
farmed fish in this recent study
researchers measured the levels of
pesticides like DDT uh pcbs polycylic
aromatic hydrocarbons and toxic Elements
by Mercury and lead in a large sample of
farmed and wild caught seafood and in
general they found farmed was worse
think of the suspect as farmed and
dangerous the measure measured levels of
most organic and many inorganic
pollutants were higher in the farmed
Seafood products and consequently intake
levels for the consumer if such products
were consumed so for example this is for
polycyclic hydrocarbons persistent
pesticides and pcbs significantly more
contamination in all the farmed fish
samples for all the contaminants the the
salmon and sea bass though it didn't
seem to matter for crayfish and the wild
Cott muscles were actually worse and if
you split adult and child consumers into
only eating farmed seafood or only
eating wild CAU Seafoods the level of
pluen exposure would be significantly
worse from the farmed
Seafood overall they investigated a
total of 59 pollutants and toxic
elements and taking all these data as a
whole and based on the rates of
consumption of fish and seafood the
population in Spain where the
researchers hailed from the results
indicate that a theoretical consumer who
chose to consume only farmed fish would
be exposed to levels of pollutants about
twice as high than if they would have
chosen instead wild caught fish so you
could eat twice the amount if you stuck
to Wild CAU easier said than done though
mislabeling rates for fish and other
Seafood in the US is between 30 and
38% so the average fraud rate is like 1
and
three